Hongyun Deng, Master's Candidate

School of Electronic Information and Electrical Engineering Shanghai Jiao Tong University SEIEE Building, 800 Dong Chuan Rd, Shanghai, China Phone: +86-18217508023, Email: hongyundeng@sjtu.edu.cn

Research Interests

I am a self-motivated and team-minded master's candidate with 2 years of experience in studying the numerical methods of solving the electromagnetic problems (especially the integral equation method). I am interested in applying different mathematical and physical theories and methods to solve the electromagnetic problems appearing in the microwave technology.

Education

09/2020 – present
Shanghai Jiao Tong University
M. E. Electronic Engineering
09/2016 – 06/2020
Shanghai Jiao Tong University
Shanghai, China
B. E. Electronic Engineering

Research Experiences

Shanghai, China Department of Electronic Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Studying the electromagnetic scattering problem of the moving object in the lossy medium; Developed a fast algorithm of evaluating the Doppler effect of an arbitrarily shaped object which moves uniformly in the free space using the integral equation method; Proposed a new efficient method of computing the Sommerfeld integrals appearing in the electromagnetic problem in the planar

stratified medium

03/2021 – 09/2021 Graduate Teaching Assistant

Shanghai, China Department of Electronic Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Helped Prof. Gaobiao Xiao organize the undergraduate course Theory of Electromagnetic waves;

Graded students' assignments and answered some students' questions about the course

09/2017 – 06/2019 Undergraduate Research Assistant

Shanghai, China Department of Electronic Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Studied the principles of electromagnetic metamaterials for different uses

Skills

Analyze electromagnetic problems using the integral equation method (3 years) Software engineering (FORTRAN, C/C++, MATLAB, Mathematica, 4 years) Scientific Writing and Illustration (MS Office, Latex, Visio, Adobe Illustrator, 3 years)

Awards

2022 IEEE Antennas and Propagation Society Fellowship (APSF, Application)

2022 Ceyear Scholarship, Ceyear Technologies Co., Ltd, China
2020 – 2021 Academic Scholarship, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, China

Publications

Journal Papers

- **H. Deng**, G. Xiao and G. Liu, "An Efficient Method for Calculating the Doppler Spectrum of an Arbitrarily Shaped Object in Uniform Motion," *IEEE Trans. on Antennas Propag.*, 2022, doi: 10.1109/TAP.2022.3191188. (Early Access)
- **H. Deng**, G. Xiao, and S. Huang, "New Approximate Expressions for Evaluating the Fields of a Vertical Magnetic Dipole in a Dissipative Half Space", *ACES Journal*, vol. 36, no. 11, pp. 1393–1400, Dec. 2021, doi: 10.13052/2021.ACES.J.361101.

Conference Papers

- **H. Deng**, G. Xiao, "The Numerical Analysis of the Doppler Effect of an Arbitrarily Shaped PEC Object in Uniform Motion," 2022 Asia-Pacific International Symposium on Electromagnetic Compatibility (APEMC), 2022. (Accepted)
- **H. Deng**, S. Huang and G. Xiao, "A Fast Algorithm for Computing Fields of a Vertical Magnetic Dipole in a Dissipative Half-Space," 2021 International Applied Computational Electromagnetics Society (ACES-China) Symposium, 2021, pp. 1-2.